YAN BONNEL

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ybonnel@gmail.com https://github.com/ybonnel https://twitter.com/ybonnel

Profile

Full Stack developer

12 years experience on Java development

4 years on Postgresql

3 years on modern Javascript (like React.js)

2 years on elastic search.

Skills

Java

I work with java for 12 years, I like very much community around Java, go to JUG, Devoxx,

Elasticsearch

I discover Elasticsearch 2 years ago, and i like the possibility of this product.

Postgresql

I develop with postgresql as primary storage for 4 years, i like the stability and all the features of this database.

Continuous delivery

I like to automate everything and have a real continuous delivery.

Javascript

I work with modern Javascript for 3 years with a specific framework inspired by React.js.

Infrastructure

For 4 years, I operate a complex system with 60 servers, and 2 000 req/s.

Technical

Java	Postgresql	HTML5	Jenkins
JEE	Play framework	CSS	Sonar
Kotlin	Vertx	React.js	Gradle
Spring	Android	Javascript/JQuery	Maven

Experience

Smart RX - CEGEDIM group SAAS Architect

08/2014 - now

Transversal technical leader on all SAAS application

In charge of all SAAS application for pharmacies (more than 6000 clients)

Functions:

- Proof of concept
- Knowledge share
- Support on complex problem
- Code review
- CTO help on enterprise strategy
- Technological survey

Technologies:

- Java
- Javascript/EcmaScript 2016
- Play Framwork
- Postgresql
- MemCached
- Git
- Elasticsearch (20 servers cluster)
- o Debian
- Jenkins
- Sonar
- Upsource
- Infrastructure of 70 servers.

Sopra Group Software Architect

Expert developer on the client framework (from 04/2013 to 08/2014)

Functions:

- $\circ~$ Support for all developers using the framework.
- Development of new features in framework.

Technologies:

- Java
- Maven
- SOA
- SVN

Technical leader on one Java application, team of 10 people (from 07/2013 to 03/2014)

Applications in charge of housing demand in France.

Functions

• Technical expert: support for all developers.

Technologies:

- o Java
- Maven
- o Spring
- Struts
- Axis
- o Postgresql
- Tomcat
- o SVN

$\underline{\text{Transversal technical leader on 4 Java applications, team of 30 people (from 05/2012 to 06/2013)}}$

Applications in charge of network activation for a french mobile operator.

New application management contract with reversibility.

Work in team with Indian people.

Functions:

- $\circ~$ Continuous delivery: define build and install processes with Jenkins for all applications.
- Technical expert: support for all developers.
- $\circ~$ Help to resolve issues on multiple environments.
- Realization of a Web portal for developers (Play framework).

Technologies:

- o Java
- Ant
- Jboss
- Oracle
- Unix
- o Jenkins
- Play Framework
- SVN

Technical leader on 2 Java applications, team of 100 to 200 people (02/2008 - 04-2012)

Redisign project of the core system for a french mobile operator.

This project covers from order to billing through a catalog for the offers' referential.

Functions

- Bench of Cameleon Software (used for the catalog offers) 5 months
 - Use of Load Runner.
 - Development of a webservice layer to abstract Cameleon (Jboss WS).
- Writing functionnal specifications for the catalog offers 6 months.
- o Technical leader on the catalog offers, 5 to 10 developers 1 year
 - Webservices (JbossWS),
 - Hibernate,
 - Continuous integration (Maven, Hudson, Sonar).
- Technical leader on a taking order system, 10 to 30 developers more than 2 years
 - Webservices (CXF),
 - Spring core, JPA, Hibernate,
 - Continuous integration (Maven, Jenkins, Sonar),
 - Installation and integration of Gerrit (software to help in code review),
 - Realization of a Web portal for developers (Play Framework).

Technologies:

- o Java,
- o Spring core,
- o Jboss,
- o Hibernate, JPA,
- Webservices (JbossWS and CXF),
- o Oracle,
- o Unix,
- o Maven,
- o Jenkins,
- o Play Framework,
- o SVN,
- Git (used for Web portal).

Sopra Group

Junior Software Architect

11/2007 - 01/2008

Create an UI to manage documents (team of 5 people)

Application in charge of document management for all exploitation documents.

Functions

- $\circ~$ Participation in the pre-study for realization.
- Creation of the base code for the development.

Technologies:

- Java/JEE,
- o Struts,
- Hibernate,
- SVN.

<u>Participation in every steps of an Application Management Contract (team of 4 to 10 people)</u>

Applications used for a mobile operator to know the list of network antennas which would be used by users.

Functions:

- C++ developments under Unix for an activation system.
- JEE developments for an administration interface.
- Java developments under Windows for a forecasting system radio coverage.
- Participation in specifications and testing for these applications.

Technologies:

- ∘ C++,
- o Unix/Shell,
- Java/JEE,
- o Struts,
- PVCS Version Manager,
- VBScript.

Sopra Group

Developer

02/2006 - 06/2006

Final-year internship

Participation in developing an activation system for a french mobile operator.

- C++ developments under Unix (HP UX),
- Unix Scripting (KSH).

Off-work projects

Community 2012 - 2016

Part in organisation of multiple conferences.

- http://www.breizhcamp.org/
- http://www.codeursenseine.com/

Speaker

- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cufoOv6 PxU
- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iOwnUPSYoKI
- http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aqBYnOjkX6w
- http://www.normandyjug.org/2013/09/06/une-application-web-simple-en-java-cest-possible-par-yan-bonnel/

simpledom-component

12/2016 - now

https://simpledomjs.github.io/simpledom-component/

Just an other javascript component framework!

SimpleWeb4j

2013 - 2014

https://github.com/ybonnel/SimpleWeb4j

Small java framework to create web application based on angularjs and REST services.

YboTv 12/2012 - now

https://github.com/ybonnel/ybo-tv-android

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.ybo.ybotv.android

Android application for France TV Program.

Some statistics:

- o Downloads: more than 82 000,
- Comments: more than 650 ratings with 3.96/5 average.

"Transports Rennes" and "Transports Bordeaux"

08/2010 - now

https://github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRennes

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.ybo.transportsrennes https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.ybo.transportsbordeaux

Android applications for public transportation of Rennes and Bordeaux.

Use of Open-Data for thess two cities.

Some statistics:

- o Transports Rennes' downloads: more than 83 000,
- o Transports Rennes' comments: more than 2000 ratings with 4.50/5 average,
- Transports Bordeaux' downloads: more than 96 000,
- Transports Bordeaux' comments: more than 1600 ratings with 4.49/5 average,
- Source code: more than 30 000 LOC (http://www.ohloh.net/p/TransportsRennes).

CsvEngine

2011 - 2013

https://github.com/ybonnel/CsvEngine

Small java framework based on annotations used to parse and write CSV files.

Transports Rouen

07/2012

https://github.com/ybonnel/TransportsRouen http://transports-rouen.appspot.com/

Small mobile web app for public bikes in Rouen.

Used to test JQuery Mobile technology.

Education

University of La Rochelle (France)

2000 - 2006

Master in computer sciences (specialty: pattern recognition and image processing).